mytitanium.ca 2016-11-03

# Privacy Policy | Titanium+® Prepaid Card

### [Log In](https://www.mytitanium.ca/account/login)

## INTRODUCTION

Money Mart® understands that privacy is a critical issue for all customers and is committed to protecting customer personal information. We want to earn our customers’ trust by providing safeguards to protect personal information as we continue to provide valuable products and services.

Money Mart’s Privacy Policy is designed to comply with Canada’s Federal Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act including the ten principles set out in the National Canadian Standards Association: Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information. These guidelines have been customized to meet the specific needs and expectations of Money Mart customers.

Money Mart will continue to review this Privacy Policy to ensure it remains current with changing laws and regulations while meeting the evolving needs of its customers. In the event of any amendment to the Privacy Policy, a notice will be posted on [www.moneymart.ca](http://www.moneymart.ca/) or at each Money Mart branch. 

You may view the Peoples Trust Privacy Policy by clicking on the following links: 

  * English: [Peoples Trust Privacy Policy](http://www.peoplestrust.com/legal/privacy-security/privacy/)
  * French: [La Compagnie de Fiducie Peoples - protection des renseignements](http://www.peoplestrust.com/legale/protection-des-renseignements-personnels-et-securite/politique-en-matiere-de-protection-des-renseignements-personnels/)

## DEFINITIONS

**Collection**

The act of gathering, acquiring, recording, or obtaining personal information from any source, including third parties, by any means. 

**Consent**

Voluntary agreement with the collection, use and disclosure of personal information for defined purposes. 

**Customer**

An individual who uses, or applies to use, Money Mart’s products or services. 

**Disclosure**

Making personal information available to others outside of Money Mart. 

**Personal Information**

This covers information about an identifiable individual, such as home address, home telephone number, birth date, Social Insurance Number and credit reports. Personal information does not include business contact information such as the individual’s name, title, business address, or business telephone number, business fax number or business email address. 

**Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA)**

Federal legislation that governs the collection, use and disclosure of personal information in the course of commercial activities. 

**Record**

A record of information is in any form or medium, whether written, printed, photographic or electronic form or any other form. 

**Third Party**

An individual or organization outside of Money Mart. 

**Use**

The treatment, handling, and management of personal information by and within Money Mart. 

## ACCOUNTABILITY

Money Mart is responsible for personal information under its control and has designated individuals to be accountable for Money Mart’s compliance.

Money Mart has appointed an individual to be the Privacy Officer, who is accountable overall for compliance with the Privacy Policy. On a day-to-day basis, the collection and processing of personal information is delegated to other employees within Money Mart.

Money Mart is responsible for personal information in its possession or control and will use reasonable means to provide a proper level of protection for personal information, including when personal information is being processed by a third party.

Money Mart will disclose the title of the person(s) designated to oversee compliance with the Privacy Policy upon request.

Money Mart continues to develop and refine policies and procedures to protect personal information, receive and respond to complaints and inquires, train employees and communicate this information to customers.

## IDENTIFYING PURPOSES

Money Mart will identify the purposes for which personal information is collected at or before the time the information is collected. This information may be communicated orally, electronically or in writing. 

Money Mart collects, uses and discloses personal information for the following purposes: 

  * To provide financial services to customers;
  * To develop, manage and market products and services to meet the needs of customers;
  * To obtain credit information and credit reports from credit reporting agencies to assess credit history and credit worthiness and to confirm accuracy of information provided by individuals;
  * To confirm details of customer employment;
  * To contact customers for products and services that may be of interest;
  * To determine the eligibility of customers for different products and services that may be of interest;
  * To extract certain information for the purpose of generating statistics for our internal purposes;
  * To ensure a high standard of service to customers;
  * To record, track and respond to customer feedback and complaints;
  * To meet legal and regulatory requirements;
  * To confirm the identity of a customer; and
  * To collect debt that may become owed to Money Mart by a customer.

Money Mart will identify any new purpose(s) for which personal information is being collected, used or disclosed. Customers will be informed by either posting a notice on the Money Mart website ([www.moneymart.ca](http://www.moneymart.ca/)), written notification or direct communication. 

## CONSENT

Notice will be given and consent obtained when collecting, using and disclosing personal information, except when deemed inappropriate. 

Money Mart will make a reasonable effort to ensure that all customers have an understanding of the purpose(s) for which personal information is collected, used or disclosed. 

Money Mart will obtain consent to use and disclose personal information at the time the personal information is collected. Money Mart may also obtain consent to use and disclose personal information after it has been collected, but prior to the personal information being used or disclosed for a new purpose. 

Consent shall not be obtained through deception. An individual’s consent may be explicit or implied. Consent can be given either orally, electronically or in writing. Use of products and services offered by Money Mart constitutes implied consent for the collection, use and disclosure of personal information for all identified purposes. 

Money Mart may collect, use or disclose personal information without the individual’s knowledge and consent in certain circumstances. For example:

  * When the collection, use, and disclosure is permitted or required by law;
  * When the collection, use, and disclosure is clearly in the interests of the individual and consent cannot be obtained in a timely manner;
  * When seeking the consent of the individual may defeat the purpose of collecting the information;
  * When use of the information is for an emergency that threatens the life, health or security of an individual;
  * When needed to collect a debt, to comply with a subpoena, warrant or other court order, or as otherwise required or authorized by law;
  * When the information is solely for Journalistic, Artistic, or Literary Intent; or
  * When the information is publicly available.

An individual may withdraw consent at any time subject to legal or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice. Refusal or withdrawal of consent by a customer may prevent Money Mart from providing a product or service to that customer. Money Mart will not unreasonably withhold products or services from a customer who refuses or withdraws consent, but if the personal information is required to offer the product or service, Money Mart may decline to deal with the customer who will not consent to the use of such personal information. Money Mart may be contacted for more information regarding the method by which consent can be withdrawn. 

## LIMITING COLLECTION

The collection of personal information is limited to that which is related to the identified purposes.

Personal information will be collected by fair and lawful means. Most personal information will be collected directly from employees and customers.

Money Mart may collect personal information from sources such as credit bureaus, employers, personal references, or other third parties that represent they have the right to disclose such personal information. 

## LIMITING USE, DISCLOSURE AND RETENTION

Personal information will not be used or disclosed for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the consent of the individual or as required by law.

Money Mart shares and stores customer personal and transaction information with affiliated companies of Money Mart located in the USA for the purposes listed in the Identifying Purposes section above and Money Mart keeps track of customer feedback and complaints utilizing a third party service provider whose servers are located in Europe. In addition, Money Mart may use and disclose personal information to third parties as follows: 

  * A Money Mart affiliate seeking information as an agent of the individual;
  * A Money Mart agent that will evaluate the customer’s creditworthiness or to collect a potential debt;
  * A credit reporting agency to obtain credit information and credit reports to assess credit history and credit worthiness and to confirm accuracy of information;
  * The issuer and/or payer of negotiable items to confirm identity;
  * A third party – where individual consents to disclosure;
  * A third party – where disclosure is required by law;
  * A public authority or agent of a public authority where there is imminent danger to the life or property of an individual which could be avoided or minimized by disclosure; and
  * Conduct surveys in order to enhance our products and services to meet customer needs.

Where personal information is disclosed to a third party, Money Mart will ensure that appropriate security measures are utilized to protect the use and disclosure of personal information. 

Only Money Mart employees are authorized or granted access to personal information about customers when responsibilities reasonably require access. 

Money Mart will retain personal information only as long as necessary for the fulfillment of identified purpose, or as required by law. 

## ACCURACY

Reasonable efforts will be made to ensure that personal information is as accurate, complete and up-to-date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used. 

Due to the nature of Money Mart’s business, personal information will be updated on an on-going basis as the customer utilizes Money Mart’s products and services. 

## SAFEGUARDS

Personal information will be protected by reasonable security safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the personal information. 

Money Mart is committed to the protection of personal information against loss, theft, unauthorized access, disclosure, duplication, use and modification regardless of the format in which the personal information is held. 

Money Mart will protect personal information disclosed to third parties by means of contractual agreements with respect to the confidentiality of the personal information and the purposes for which the personal information is to be used. 

Money Mart will use reasonable security measures in the disposal of personal information. 

The protection of personal information is an ongoing process, and Money Mart will update and review the reasonableness of the security safeguards as needed. 

## OPENNESS

Information is available to individuals regarding Money Mart’s policies and procedures relating to the management of personal information. Efforts have been made to make these policies and procedures understandable and easily available, either in written or electronic format. 

Money Mart will make the following information available: 

  * Name, title and address of the Privacy Officer;
  * Means of gaining access to personal information held by Money Mart;
  * A brief description of the type of personal information retained by Money Mart and a general account of its use; and
  * A copy of any brochure or other information that explains Money Mart’s privacy policies and procedures.

## INDIVIDUAL ACCESS

Upon written request, and within a reasonable period of time, a customer will be informed of the existence, use, and disclosure of his or her personal information and will be given access to that information. An individual is entitled to comment on the accuracy and completeness of his or her personal information, and have that information amended where appropriate. 

Money Mart will respond to an individual request within a reasonable time period and at a minimal cost to the customer. The information will be made available within 30 days of the request and the cost will vary with the type and amount of information requested. Individuals can seek access to their personal information by submitting a written request to the Privacy Officer as follows: 

Privacy Officer  
---  
National Money Mart Company  
703 Evans Ave., Suite 600  
Etobicoke, ON  
M9C 5E9  
Canada  
  
An individual will be required to provide sufficient personal information to confirm their identity with Money Mart. 

An individual shall be able to challenge the accuracy and completeness of their personal information and have it amended as appropriate. Money Mart will amend personal information when a customer successfully demonstrates the inaccuracy or incompleteness of their personal information. Any unresolved disagreements relating to the accuracy and completeness of an individual’s personal information will be noted for so long as such information remains relevant. 

Money Mart may not be able to provide access to any or all of an individual’s personal information. If a request for personal information is denied, Money Mart will notify the individual in writing, documenting reasons for refusal and resources available for redress. 

Reasons for refusing access may include: 

  * That the personal information is unreasonably costly to provide;
  * That the release of the personal information may threaten the life or security of a third party;
  * That the personal information is subject to or generated in a formal dispute resolution process;
  * That the personal information cannot be disclosed for legal, security, or commercial proprietary reasons; or
  * That the personal information is subject to solicitorclient or litigation privilege.

## COOKIES AND PIXEL TAGS (WWW.MONEYMART.CA)

Cookies are small data files placed on a user’s computer by a website. They may store and transmit information to websites that users visit. [www.moneymart.ca](http://www.moneymart.ca/) uses cookies on our website to: 

  * Help provide our on-line products and services to users
  * Market those products and services
  * Analyze the flow of traffic to our website
  * Analyze and track the traffic of website users from page to page within our website

Third party vendors, including Google®, may: 

  * Show our ads on websites on the internet
  * Use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to our website

Users may accept or decline cookies through the configuration settings of their web-browser. Users may also opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page. 

Pixel tags (or clear gifs) are small, transparent graphic images placed on a website or in an email that are not normally visible to the user. They provide non-identifiable information about your usage of the website. [www.moneymart.ca](http://www.moneymart.ca/) uses pixel tags to: 

  * Note pages visited on our website
  * Assist in the administration of affiliate accounts

## CHALLENGING COMPLIANCE

Individuals can address any challenge concerning compliance with the Privacy Policy to Money Mart’s designated Privacy Officer.

To contact the Privacy Officer at Money Mart:

Privacy Officer  
---  
National Money Mart Company  
703 Evans Ave., Suite 600  
Etobicoke, ON  
M9C 5E9  
Canada  
Email: [privacyofficer@moneymart.ca](mailto:privacyofficer@moneymart.ca)  
Website: [www.moneymart.ca](http://www.moneymart.ca/)  
  
Money Mart will investigate all complaints. The customer will be informed of the outcome of the investigation regarding his or her complaint. 

If the Privacy Officer is unable to satisfy the customer’s concerns, the customer may then refer to the Privacy Commissioner of Canada at 1-800-282-1376 or [info@privcom.gc.ca](mailto:info@privcom.gc.ca) and, if appropriate, file a written complaint with that office. However, the customer is encouraged to use Money Mart’s internal information and complaint procedures first. 

### Buy! Register! Load! Use!

Order your Titanium+ Prepaid MasterCard here online or pick up a card at any Money Mart store. Learn More
